( " Mosien " )
( - a ghost that appears as a monkey or a child . )
( Taking advantage of one 's sense of guilt , )
( it makes people lose their minds ... )
Lin Li-shui
( Missing Person )
Shui .
Come back soon .
I 'm waiting for you to sing together .
( Yi-chun : Have you got up , lazy boy ? )
( Just got off work . Goodnight ! )
Wei .
Get up .
Get up !
Fuck !
Why didn 't the alarm go off ?
Grandma .
Grandma , why didn 't you wake me up ?
Grandma , did you turn my alarm off ?
No , and I tried to wake you up .
It 's alright . Come have breakfast !
You didn 't come home till four in the morning .
You slept for only few hours .
One needs six to eight hours ' sleep .
I can 't afford that now !
You work so hard every day .
You 're bound to ruin your health !
Always come home so late .
You hadn 't come home when I got up !
Hey , sit down and eat properly , okay ?
What 's her name ? She 's coming for dinner tonight ?
Yi-chun . Shen Yi-chun .
It 's better to eat at home .
Food in the restaurants isn 't clean .
Home-made food is clean and safe .
Right , listen to me .
You keep quiet when she is here .
Let me question her tonight .
Why don 't you get married after four , five years ?
Why ?
We 're not good enough for her ?
If you 're going to talk nonsense , I won 't bring her home .
You 're always like this when I bring it up .
Hey , you !
Your lunch box !
Lunch " .
Silly boy .
Shu-fang .
Ho Wen Shu-fang .
Shui .
Hello . Good morning everyone !
I 'm Yi-chun , the stand-in DJ for today .
It 's time for Love Moring Roll-call !
What exactly is the end of love ?
Marriage ?
Some say marriage is the tomb of love .
I wonder how you feel about it .
Let 's take some calls .
Oh ...
Yeah , it 's really the tomb .
I have to look after not only my kids but parents-in-law .
I 'm working like a slave .
And have to serve my difficult mother-in-law .
Hui-chun , have you discussed it with your husband ?
Yes .
Whenever we talk about his mom ,
he gets angry .
His mom is always right .
But he has only one mother .
What can I do ?
Okay , thanks for your call .
My boyfriend 's grandma
nags all the time .
But actually , I envy you as you 've family with you .
Not everyone is as lucky as you ...
( Grandma )
Let me play you a nice song first .
We 'll take more calls after the break .
Good morning , everyone !
Good morning , sir !
Okay , let 's shout the slogan .
Sincerity is everything !
Chu-shan Estate Agency !
Professional ! Reliable !
Energetic !
Yes ?
There is room for negotiation .
( Grandma )
Hi , Mr. Ho . Here we are !
Mr. and Mrs. Lin .
Let 's go up .
105 square meters .
At the end of the block , it 's light .
It feels airy with all these windows .
If we are done here ,
let 's go back to the office and go over the details .
Sure .
Please wait for me outside .
Let me turn the light off .
Yes
Grandma ?
( Call Grandma )
Let 's ask him .
Mr. Ho , shall we go ?
Yes , sorry for keep you waiting .
Let 's go back to the office .
It 's 9.45 in the evening .
I 'm Yi-chun .
Thank you for listening to our program .
Wish you a very good evening .
Goodnight .
Yi-chun , I 'm sorry .
This is my daughter .
Bei-bei .
Don 't run around in the studio , understand ?
Say hello to Auntie Yi-chun .
Auntie Yi-chun
Bei-bei , how old are you ?
I 'm three years old .
Bei-bei .
Three is like this .
Don 't run around like this .
You 'll disturb their work .
How come you have time to see me tonight ?
Haven 't seen you for ages !
Thought you might have eloped with someone !
Oh , well . Good to know you 're worried .
Hey .
Grandma has cooked a lot .
Let 's eat at home , alright ?
Please ...
Alright .
Does Grandma remember my name or not ?
Yes , she does .
She definitely does !
Does she remember yours ?
Of course she remembers mine !
Yeah ?
Let me take you to a place first .
What place ?
Guess !
You 're selling it ?
Miss . Shen .
A luxurious four-bedroom family apartment .
Brand new steel and concrete structure .
Windows on all walls .
You 've got the most beautiful view of Taipei city !
Even playing a song ? !
My latest service .
Viewing the property
while dancing !
Here is the living room .
Oh !
I 'm going to put an enormous sofa
in here .
Your music doesn 't go well with your dance !
Come !
Come see this room .
This one ...
It 's the master bedroom .
It comes with a brand new double bed .
Come . Come .
Don 't jump into someone 's bed !
- So soft . - What ?
It 'll get dirty .
Let 's get down .
Okay , let 's get down .
I 'm getting down ...
You 're acting so weird today .
Wait .
You 've got any condom with you ?
We 'll get married anyway .
If you get pregnant , we 'll have a child !
Who wants to have a child with you ?
Or who do you want have children with ?
Well .
Haven 't we talked about it so many times ?
I 'll be angry if you do it again .
This property ...
I already paid the deposit .
You did ?
How much did you pay ?
I mortgaged Grandma 's house
and paid the deposit .
The rest is enough for the first year 's payment .
- Within a year ... - Did you
tell Grandma about it ?
Trust me , the location is good .
In two years , the price is bound to soar .
I can make at least five million when I sell it .
And then we can get married and have children ...
But it 's all in the future ...
We won 't be able buy it when the price soars up .
No , it 's not the problem .
What if Grandma thinks it 's my idea ?
She won 't think it 's your idea .
How do you know ?
Okay .
If you insist on buying ,
you move in with Grandma .
I 'll live in my own place .
I marry you because I want to live with you .
What do you mean me living with Grandma ?
And you still live in your place ?
No .
Marriage isn 't in my plan .
How many times have we talked about it ?
Why don 't you want to get married ?
Why in a hurry ?
We 've been together for five years .
Five years !
What else do we need ?
- What is not there ? - I 've told you that
marriage isn 't in my plan !
I 'm exhausted .
I haven 't slept
for twenty-four hours .
Do we have to talk about it today ?
I 'm sorry .
Grandma , Yi-chun is here !
Grandma has cooked a lot of food .
Need any help to re-heat it ?
Yeah , thanks .
Grandma ?
Grandma ...
You 're going out ?
Shui 's come back .
I 'm going to hers for karaoke .
Auntie Shui 's back ?
It 's late to meet up !
Grandma , I need to talk to you about something .
You 're still angry at me ?
The pig trotter was really yummy .
I ate it all .
Don 't stay out too late !
Wei .
Who are you talking to ?
Grandma .
Grandma ?
She seems a bit angry at me ...
Never mind , let 's eat on our own .
( Ho Wen Shu-fang Day 1 )
Shui !
Come on , everyone !
Shui 's back !
Fuck !
Grandma , don 't turn my alarm off again , okay ? !
You 're back after seven days !
It 's truly god 's blessing .
I told you firecrackers worked !
Did you eat anything ?
- See ? - We should have done it earlier !
We really should !
Good we let off firecrackers . Safety is everything .
You made us so worried .
Uncle Kun .
Did you see my grandma ?
No .
Ah , she ...
Now she ...
- Did anyone call her family ? - Yeah .
- Go tell them . - Auntie Shui .
Tell them she 's back .
It 's good you 're safe .
We were so worried .
Did you see my grandma ?
I 'm sorry ...
I 'm sorry .
What are you sorry for ?
It 's not my fault .
What happened ?
Don 't be fooled by her !
Shui , what are you sorry for ?
I 'm sorry .
A parcel for Ho Chih-wei .
Everyone is having so much fun !
Everyone , look over here .
Lin Li-shui , look !
You can 't call people 's full names in the mountains !
And don 't pat people on their shoulders .
Why not ?
If you call someone 's full name ,
and he turns around ,
he 'll be caught to replace someone else in the woods .
Really ?
Hey , do you smell something weird ?
- Do you ? - I caught the smell just now .
It smells like a dead rat .
No , it 's not the smell of a dead rat .
Well , I think the toilet is blocked .
Really ? How come I can 't smell it ?
How can you not smell it ? It 's really bad !
Didn 't you take the garbage out ?
It smells rotten .
It 's so dirty !
Uncle Kun .
Is this Auntie Shui 's camera ?
Yes , it 's Shui 's camera .
How did you get it ?
Do you know where Auntie Shui 's house is ?
Here is her house .
Why is the door left open ?
They were here when I came this morning .
How could this happen ?
Let me find the light switches .
What are you doing ?
Nothing .
Come help me !
I haven 't turned the power on yet .
Are you all right ?
( Grandma , whenever you come back . )
( Please wake me up , okay ? )
( Love , Wai )
It 's captured on the morning
your grandma went missing .
Here , look !
See ?
Your grandma was going out .
Grandma doesn 't walk like that .
We didn 't came home till the evening .
It means grandma wasn 't there .
Wait , wind back a bit .
Okay .
Here , wind back a bit .
Here .
Look at this ...
Now I 'd like to ask you
to do me a favor .
Grandma Ho has gone missing since
she left home on 16th April .
Her family are really worried about her .
Please call us if you see someone who fits the description .
She 's 75-year-old ...
That kind of ghosts live in the mountains .
His grandma didn 't go to the mountains recently .
How could she be caught ?
The trees in the mountains have been chopped down .
The spectres now have no place to live .
So they come down here to catch people .
Wei , don 't worry .
Old people often wander off and get lost .
Don 't worry . She 'll be back .
Come on , let 's let off the firecrackers .
Come on . Stand aside .
Let 's let off firecrackers .
Wei .
Get up .
Get up !
Slowly . Eat more !
Wow , it 's so yummy !
Really yummy ?
Careful , don 't get your clothes dirty .
Or you won 't look good on the ceremony .
Come , have another egg .
Grandma , you 're a super cook !
Really ?
Okay .
Here .
Wei .
When you grow up ,
promise you 'll often eat with Grandma .
Okay ?
Don 't be like your father . Come , eat up !
Okay !
I 'll eat with you every day !
Okay , good boy .
I 'll write it down .
Remember it .
Okay .
I 'll remember it .
What are you doing ?
Ho Chih-wei .
( Ho Chih-wei promises to eat with his grandma every day )
You got up ?
I did try to wake you .
What happened to you ?
What 's up ?
Say something . What 's up ?
I 'm just
haven 't hug you for a long time .
Okay .
Okay , grandma lets you hug .
Don 't cry , good boy .
Bring your ...
What 's her name ?
Shen Yi-chun .
Oh , okay .
Shen Yi-chun . Bring her home for dinner .
Okay ?
We 'll have dinner together like family .
Okay .
Hello everyone , welcome back .
We 're going to take the last call .
It 's from Shu-hui in Kaohsiung .
Hello Shu-hui .
He doesn 't love me anymore .
Shu-hui , who doesn 't love you anymore ?
Shu-hui , you may need to speak up a little .
Or neither I nor other listeners
can hear you .
He doesn 't love me anymore .
Okay , Shu-hui .
No matter who he is ,
we women have to be strong and independent .
And I ...
Hello ?
Well .
We may have problems with the line .
But it 's okay .
At the end of the show ,
I 'd like to say to all women .
No matter he loves you or not ,
you have to learn to love yourself .
Be brave when a relationship comes to an end .
The next show is Ten p.m. Roll-call .
Now let 's hear a cheerful song .
See you next time .
Bye-Bye
Why do you suddenly show up ?
- Are you all right ? - Grandma
invites you to dinner at home tonight .
Grandma 's back ?
Let 's have dinner at home tonight .
You 're sweating .
What happened ? Are you feeling sick ?
Come home for dinner with me .
Okay .
Let 's go see a doctor before going home .
Come on .
You look horrible .
Sit here .
Here .
Wait for me .
I 'd like to see a doctor .
- First visit ? - Yes .
Your health insurance card , please .
Here , fill in the form .
Ho Chih-wei , what are you doing ?
Don 't you think babies are so cute ?
Hurry up , come see a doctor !
Why don 't you want to marry me ?
Quiet . You 're disturbing the babies .
Do we have to talk about it now ?
Why don 't you want to have a baby ?
Can you afford it ?
What on earth are you talking about ?
Come , let 's go see a doctor .
I want to go home and eat with Grandma .
Ho Chih-wei !
Grandma , I brought Yi-chun back for dinner .
Pork rib stew .
Braised rump pork .
Uncle Kun !
Come on , quick !
- What happened ? - Wei ...
What happened ?
Wei ...
Wei is ...
What happened ?
Wei ... He was here just now !
( Ho Chih-wei Day 1 )
Gods in Heaven . Gods in the Netherworld .
Please perform a miracle for us !
Yi-chun , we had better burn that too .
Come ...
Yi-chun , here is the last trick .
It 's the most important one ...
Repeat after me .
Louder !
Muster your strength .
Dear mountain gods ,
we 're asking you for help .
Please protect us .
Go back to hell , you ghosts !
You motherfucker !
Back to the mountains ! Don 't make trouble here !
Well , say ...
That 's enough for you .
Come on , louder !
You motherfucker ! Go back !
Louder !
Fuck ! Go away ! I 'm not scared of you !
Fuck !
I 'd like you to help me with one thing .
Mr. Ho Chih-wei left home around midnight on
20th April and has gone missing since then .
His family are really worried about him .
- Wish you - Hello ma 'am .
- Can help me - Are you looking for a new home ?
I can help you with any property you need .
Ho is about 26-year-old .
178cm in height .
Male with short hair .
He was wearing a pale blue shirt
And black pants .
If you see him ,
please call
the local police station .
Or call the radio station
so we can relay the info to his family .
So his family could find him soon .
Now it 's you .
Here !
The police saw her .
She had nothing with her .
The police found her walking on the motorway .
So many people ...
So many threes ...
Grandma is fine .
Just a bit dehydrated .
So scary ...
Her mental status is very unstable .
There 's someone ...
So many threes ...
Mrs. Ho , Yi-chun has come to see you .
Mrs. Ho .
..
I called Wei 's name ...
- Grandma , relax . - I called Wei 's name ...
Take a deep breath .
I called Wei 's name !
- Calm down . - I called Wei 's name !
Take a deep breath .
Grandma .
Grandma , relax .
- I called Wei 's name ... - Take a deep breath .
I called Wei 's name !
Why vomiting like that ?
I bet she was taken to the mountains by the ghost .
That day ...
You thought it was Wei .
But it was the spectre .
It was in Shui 's house .
And now
it 's gone to Mrs. Ho 's place .
Come over !
( " Mosien " )
( Walk up to the mountains )
( It 's where spectres often show up . )
( We two were turning that way . )
( But we saw his brother keep walking ahead . )
( Rumor has it that )
( " mosiens " make people lose their minds ... )
( Call your full name . )
I told my friend
we should wake him up .
But we couldn 't ...
( Woman in her eighties missing for two days . )
( We couldn 't find the way back . )
( We let off firecrackers and walked back . )
( When in the supernatural world , )
( if you let off firecrackers )
( or use explosive , )
( you can break the spell and return . )
It 'll destroy the supernatural power .
Yes , it 'll be destroyed .
( To the mountains )
( and someone talked to her . )
( Now they say that )
( the little girl in red )
( wants to take her to the mountains . )
( But she 's malicious . )
There seem to be a lot of spectres .
If it was only one or two , it was fine .
All the stories sound similar .
Lin Huo-kun .
Miss Shen , the thing is ...
I 'd like to tell you what happened the other day .
We thought Mrs. Ho might have food poisoning .
So we ran a test on her vomit .
And we found this . Please have a look .
It 's a moth chrysalis .
And it 's still alive .
My colleague at the Toxicology says
it 's " death 's-head hawk-moth " .
A very rare species of insect .
We have no idea
why it ended up in her stomach .
This is what I need to tell you .
( Death 's-head hawk-moth )
Grandma , you take a good rest .
I 'm off to work . I 'll come back after work .
When Wei comes back ,
tell him
I 'll leave this house to him .
We were quite well off .
But we lost our fortune .
So Wei
works very hard to make money .
Ask him not to work so hard
and spend more time with you .
Can you get the box for me ?
It 's over there .
Grandma .
She came to me again last night .
Who ?
She says she can take me to see Wei .
She needs a pair of shoes .
I should be the one taken away , not you guys .
It should be me .
What are you talking about ?
Grandma , please don 't think too much .
Wei must love you so much .
So he didn 't call your name .
Uncle Kun .
Could you please keep an eye on Grandma ?
Please ... I 'm running late for work .
Please make sure she doesn 't wander off .
Thank you !
Thanks !
Just before we end the program ,
I wonder if you can do me a favor .
I saw a species of moth on the Internet .
It 's called " death 's-head hawk-moth " .
Very little about it can be found online .
So if anyone
knows about their habitat ,
where you can see them ,
or if you have any relevant information ,
you 're welcome to call me at the radio station .
Thank you for listening to our program tonight .
See you next time .
Goodnight .
Bei-bei , it 's closed !
Yi-chun , we 're off !
Bye bye , auntie .
Hello .
( Wanlongkeng , Shenkengao )
Sir , can you say it again , please ?
She says she 's going to the mountains to find her .
Find whom ?
Her ...
She says she 's going to the mountain to find her .
Did she say which mountain she 's going ?
Wanlongkeng !
Excuse me .
Are you her family ?
Yes , I 'm her family .
You know in which county it is ?
Shenkengao or something sounds like that ...
Could you check it for me ?
Yes , let me check it .
Wait a minute .
Everyone 's gone to Wanlongkeng . Everyone !
Everyone 's gone to find her .
( Chun , I 'll definitely marry you in five years . )
You sure he 's your boyfriend ?
Please sign these papers
to confirm you join the mission voluntarily
and understand all the risks involved .
Our mission is
to find your boyfriend and his grandma .
If you get lost in the mountains ,
here 's a whistle .
Blow the whistle at once
and hang the red strips on the trees .
Then we 'll find you .
Here .
Take a few emergency flares
with you .
Apart from lighting ,
it 'll scare the beasts off .
Can you keep UP ?
Yeah ...
Grandma ?
Grandma !
Captain !
Grandma is over there .
Grandma is over there !
- Grandma ! - Med , over here !
- Grandma ! - Yeah . The paramedics are here .
Grandma .
Miss .
Excuse me , miss .
- Excuse me . - Sorry .
Grandma .
You go back !
- You go back or she 'll catch you . - Grandma , what did you say ?
Excuse me , we need to take her back first .
You go back !
We need to go .
Grandma , what did you say ?
You go back or she 'll catch you .
Go back ! Go back ! Go back !
Roger that .
Miss Shen .
Do you recognise the shoes ?
They 're my boyfriend 's old shoes .
You still want to come with us ?
Miss Shen . Have it .
Thanks .
First time to spend a night in the mountains ?
Yes .
Don 't be scared .
They 're scared of us too .
If we respect each other and coexist in harmony ,
they won 't do you any harm .
A lot of people went missing in the mountains ?
Legend has it that
every tree has a soul .
If you cut down a tree for no good reason ,
the mountain will capture a person and
plant the person 's soul in the mountains .
Plant ? How ?
I don 't really know .
Because " .
I 've never been planted .
Well , if Bin gets planted one day ,
you 'll be the first to know !
By the way ,
how did you know your boyfriend
came to this mountain ?
A retired mountain guide told me .
His name is Wang Tien-tze .
Told you ?
HOW ?
You know Mr. Wang ?
Sure .
He 's our patron saint .
He built all the paths
you see around here .
He phoned me in my office
and told me about Wanlongkeng .
You must be joking , right ?
No ' ?
But ...
He died a long time ago .
My grandpa told me
he was a mountain guide
during the Japanese occupation .
Captain .
The road splits .
It 's splits into three directions .
We 're breaking into three small groups .
Erge ,
take the two seniors and go down Gu Line .
Li , you and Yi-lin cut through the hill .
The rest follow me on Ling Line .
Miss Shen ,
you come with me .
Report to me on radio every hour .
Any questions ?
No !
Okay , let 's go .
Are you okay ?
Yes , I 'm okay .
Hey , I 'm here !
Hey !
Chih-Wei !
Yi-chun .
Shen Yi-chun .
Mommy .
He doesn 't love me anymore ...
Mommy , why didn 't you want me ?
Mommy , why did you get rid of me ?
Mommy .
Mommy , why didn 't you want me ?
I 'm sorry .
You 're up ?
Come have breakfast .
What happened to you ?
I had a nightmare .
I couldn 't find you .
Don 't be scared .
I 'm here . You 've found me .
Eat something .
Let me get you a glass of milk .
Where 's Grandma ?
She 's in the nursing home .
Nursing home ?
Why ?
She 's been there for two years .
We agreed to it .
You didn 't want to live with her , did you ?
Are you really okay ?
You 're asking weird questions !
You don 't want to eat ?
Come , let me feed you .
I 'm not hungry .
Okay , you can eat later .
What 's wrong ?
You 're acting so weird today .
Take me to see Grandma .
Finish your breakfast first .
Then I 'll take you there , okay ?
Let 's go .
Where are you going ?
I 'll take you there later .
Chih-Wei !
Ho Chih-wei !
Come on , Ho Chih-wei !
Ho Chih-wei , wake up !
Come !
No ...
Hurry UP !
One must stay .
Yi-chun , you go !
I 'll stay .
Yi-chun .
Leave , now !
Let 's go together .
Bei-bei , how old are you ?
I 'm three years old .
Mommy , why did you get rid of me ?
I 'm sorry .
Why don 't you want to get married ?
I 've told you marriage isn 't in my plan .
( Chun , I 'll definitely marry you in five years . )
Give me my Ho Chih-wei back !
Chih-Wei !
Hello everyone .
It 's 3.20 in the afternoon .
I 'm Yi-chun and I 've been very happy these days .
I wonder if you 've thought about
what you want most
in your life ?
Is it a successful career ?
Or simple happiness in life ?
Or you just want to sit down for dinner
with your beloved family ?
I think , in fact ,
in everyone 's heart grows a forest .
Don 't let our stubbornness damage it .
Remember to leave some time for yourselves .
From time to time , we should air
our secrets in the sun .
Next let 's hear a beautiful song .
See you next time !